
1. Sample Space
   > In probability theory, the outcomes of a random experiment are usually represented as a set.
     eg- we can represent the outcomes of a die roll as a set: outcomes={1,2,3,4,5,6}
   > A set is a collection of distinct objects, which means each outcome must occur only once in a set:
   > we also use curly braces to write a set: {Heads, Tails} is a set, while [Heads, Tails] is not a set.
   > In probability theory, the set of all possible outcomes is called a sample space. 
   >  A sample space is often denoted by the capital Greek letter Ω (read "omega") eg- Ω={1,2,3,4,5}

2. Probability of events
   > sample space is a set containing all the possible outcomes of a random experiment 
   > We can also represent event E as a set
     Consider the event "getting an even number when rolling a die , E={2,4,6}
     p({2,4,6})=no of successful events/total no of possible outcomes= 3/6=0.5

3. Certain and Impossible Events
   > The probability of an impossible event is  0,eg- sum greater than 12
      The probability of a certain event is  1, eg-  sum lower than 15 in rolling two dice is certain event as max dice value is 6 so 6+6 =12 is max 
   > The probability of any event ranges between 0 and 1

4. Addition Rule
   > P(A or B) — the probability of getting event A or event B
     To calculate P(A or B), we can also use the formula, which is called the addition rule
     p(A or B)= P(A) + P(B)
   > Addition rule can bew extended for more than two events
     P(A or B or ..or N)=P(A) + P(B)...+P(N)

5.  Venn Diagrams
    > In probability, we can visualize events using Venn diagrams.
    

6. Exceptions to the Addition Rule
   >  addition rule doesn't work for events that share corresponding outcomes  
   > To solve the problem, we need to subtract the probability of the shaded area such that we add it only once

7.  Mutually Exclusive events
   > Events that don't intersect are called mutually exclusive
   >  If two events are mutually exclusive, it means they can't happen both at the same time — if one of the events happens, 
      the other cannot possibly happen and vice-versa.
   > Events that intersect are called mutually non-exclusive
      Mutually non-exclusive events can happen at the same time, and examples include:
      Getting a number greater than 2 (event one) and getting an odd number (event two) when we roll a regular six-sided die — we could get a 5,
      which is both greater than 2 (event one) and odd (event two).
   > For mutually non-exclusive events,we don't include the area of intersection twice in our calculations 
      (the area of intersection corresponds to the situation where both events happen)
     p(A or B)=P(A) +P(B) - P(A and B)
   
8. Set Notation
   > In set theory, when we say "set A or set B," we are referring to a single set that is the result of the union between set A and set B.
   >  In set theory, we use the symbol ∪ to represent union:
   > When we say "set A and set B," we are referring to a single set that contains all the unique elements that occur in both A and B. 
   > In set theory, "and" operation is called intersection and is represented by the symbol ∩
   > P(A or B) becomes P(A ∪ B)
     P(A and B) becomes P(A ∩ B)



    
In this mission, we learned a few important things:

The addition rule for mutually exclusive and non-exclusive events.
How to represent events and sample space on Venn diagrams.
How to use set notation in probability.



  


